<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Tony Tsai</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Tony Tsai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Narrative Outline of My Talk at the 10th China R Conference</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-05-23-narrative-outline-of-my-talk-at-the-10th-china-r-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-05-23-narrative-outline-of-my-talk-at-the-10th-china-r-conference/</guid>
      <description>The 10th China R Conference was held in Tsinghua University during May 19 - 21. I initialized the session of R in Public Health. Though it was my first time to organize a session, to invite speakers, and to host it, the session was successful. The number of audiences was more than 55 persons and beyond my expectation, and the discussions were enthusiastic. I believe that via my talk more Chinese have know the R Epidemics Consortium (RECON) and they may try to use RECON packages to facilitate their epidemics research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of Disk Usage for animint</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-08-09-optimization-of-disk-usage-for-animint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-08-09-optimization-of-disk-usage-for-animint/</guid>
      <description>Problem The easy test for becoming a potential student of animint project for GSoC 2015 is to use animint to visualize some data from your domain of expertise, and upload your visualization to the web using animint2gist. I used animint to visualize the data from the CDC&amp;rsquo;s State-level FluView, which is a main data source of my Ph.D. influenza research. The script for generating the FluView viz can be found in AnimintTest repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operator for Extracting Named List Elements to Variables</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-05-21-operator-for-extracting-named-list-elements-to-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-05-21-operator-for-extracting-named-list-elements-to-variables/</guid>
      <description>In routine data analysis, I often need to convert list elements into variables. For exampple, when I create a function returning multiple values and I would like to use those values as variables separately, as only one object can be returned by the function, the common way to accomplish this task is that multiple values are combined as a list returned by the function, elements of interest are then extracted and assigned to variables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stratified Importance Sampling</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-04-20-stratified-importance-sampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-04-20-stratified-importance-sampling/</guid>
      <description>The following R codes implement the Example 5.13 in Statistical Computing with R, and compare the estimate \(\hat{\theta}\) and \(\hat{\sigma}\) from stratified importance sampling to the results from importance sampling. The example illustrates that stratification can reduce the varinace of importance sampling estimator.
M &amp;lt;- 100000 # number of replicates g &amp;lt;- function(x) { exp(-x - log(1 + x^2)) * (x &amp;gt; 0) * (x &amp;lt; 1) } # importance sampling u &amp;lt;- runif(M) # f3, inverse transform method x &amp;lt;- -log(1 - u * (1 - exp(-1))) fg &amp;lt;- g(x) / (exp(-x) / (1 - exp(-1))) (theta.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>